Guide to the Ben E. Douglas, Sr. papers, 1935-1981 and undated, bulk 1953-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Ben E. Douglas, Sr. papers 1935-1981 and undated, bulk 1953-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Douglas, Ben E., 1895-1981.
3.5 Linear Feet 817 Items
Ben E. Douglas, Sr. (1895-1981) was a politician, developer, and mayor of Charlotte, N.C. from 1935-1941.
Collection contains three folders of correspondence with friends, family, business associates, and political figures; clippings; a small amount of printed material; addresses and writings; and over 100 photographs, including 22 autographed photographs of such notables as Gen. John Pershing, Eddie Rickenbacker, Gov. Luther Hodges, Eddie Cantor, and Gene Autry. There is relatively little material relating to Douglas' service as mayor, however, there are some items that refer to his failed Congressional campaign of 1956. Also included are three scrapbooks showing the development of N.C. during the period from 1953-955, when Douglas was Director of the N.C. Dept. of Conservation and Development, nine volumes of Douglas Airport studies and plans, and three boxes of papers relating to his work on the Airport Advisory Committee, including meeting minutes, letters, memos, clippings, reports, and airport plans.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Provenance
The Ben E. Douglas, Sr. papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1982.
Collection Overview
Collection contains three folders of correspondence with friends, family, business associates, and political figures; clippings; a small amount of printed material; addresses and writings; and over 100 photographs, including 22 autographed photographs of such notables as Gen. John Pershing, Eddie Rickenbacker, Gov. Luther Hodges, Eddie Cantor, and Gene Autry. There is relatively little material relating to Douglas' service as mayor, however, there are some items that refer to his failed Congressional campaign of 1956. Also included are three scrapbooks showing the development of N.C. during the period from 1953-955, when Douglas was Director of the N.C. Dept. of Conservation and Development, nine volumes of Douglas Airport studies and plans, and three boxes of papers relating to his work on the Airport Advisory Committee, including meeting minutes, letters, memos, clippings, reports, and airport plans.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Douglas, Ben E., Sr., 1895-1981
Douglas Municipal Airport
North Carolina. Department of Conservation and Development
Aeronautics, Commercial -- North Carolina
Airports -- Planning
Charlotte (N.C.)--History
North Carolina -- Economic conditions
North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1951-
Photographs
Scrapbooks
Contents of Collection
- Ben E. Douglas, Sr. Papers, 1935-1981 and undated, (7 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1980 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Addresses and writings, 1956-1977 and undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellany, 1935-1975 and undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1940-1981 (Box 2)
  - Printed Material, 1939-1980 (Box 2)
  - Pictures (Box 2)
  - Douglas Municipal Airport: Papers, 1957-1968 (Box 3)
  - Douglas Municipal Airport: Papers, 1969-1977 (Box 4)
  - Douglas Municipal Airport: Papers, 1978-1981 and undated (Box 5)
  - Douglas Municipal Airport: Clippings, 1935-1965, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Douglas Municipal Airport: Volumes, 1968-1972, (4 volumes: Studies and Master plan) (Box 6)
  - Douglas Municipal Airport: Volumes, 1972-1980, (5 volumes: Reports, Studies, Master plan) (Box 7)
- Other Manuscript Volumes
  - Clippings scrapbook on NC Development (Volume F:7014)
  - Clippings scrapbook on NC Development (Volume F:7015)
  - Clippings scrapbook on NC Development (Volume F:7016)